NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION
Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com
Genghis Khan Laws say ''If you are served
a beverage at the lands of your enemy...
...you should always make sure it's
not poisoned.''
One way or another you will get to taste
it.
We will have a feast the day you die.
Let her go!
You bloodless.
Aunt!
No! Don't do it!
Let her go!
Let them go!
Balgay!
You tormented us enough already!
Nobody can question me and my people.
Who do you think you are?
You sneaky rat.
Let Selcan Hatun go!
You are going to kill her!
Please! Let her go!
It's enough I said!
Can't you understand?
Enough!
My Valiants!
My brothers!
The duty calls us.
Our swords will say the last words!
Are we going to wait for Osman Bey?
My sweet child, we can wait but there is
one thing.
The enemy will not wait.
Another thing.
Bala Hatun.
Gonca Hatun.
You should tell Sheikh Edebali...
...that we are about to fight our foes.
Tell him exactly that...
If the warriors of Kayı come back, they
will do so as war veterans.
If they will not survive, however, as
martyrs.
Let his prayers be with us.
Farewell.
I will gouge out your eyes so that you
will understand...
...what mixing my beverage with poison
means.
Enough!
Is your power enough only for a Hatun?
You dog!
Gündüz!
Balgay!
I said enough.
Don't you understand?
Father!
Dündar!
Gündüz!
My Allah please help us.
Let my father go!
Father!
Shepherd's dog, oh shepherd's dog,
Who will guard the sheep if you also die
now?
Please let him go!
Today is the day Ahis and Gaziyans work
side by side.
You should urgently go to my father
and tell him everything.
You?
We should find out more.
I will stay here.
May Allah be with you.
You too, Gonca.
Mother!
Honorable enemies...
...should not die like
insects.
Osman once said his root goes back all way
to Oguz Khan.
In Mongol traditions, relatives of Khan...
...get tied up to be chewed by
the horses.
Because we think bad luck will come...
...if their blood spills on our land.
Take these ones to jail.
Brother!
My son!
Leave me alone!
I said leave me alone!
I will hunt the herd.
While shepherd's dog Dündar watches me
doing it.
Brother!
Ayşe!
Now!
All of you will see what happens when
you don't obey...
...the commands of Mongols.
Don't touch me.
To die is to meet my Rab for me.
I will die with my honor.
Let me go!
Gündüz Bey!
Gündüz!
My son!
Batur Bey!
My Allah, please don't test me with child
loss.
Balgay.
You tortured us enough already, I said.
It's time, my sons!
Come on!
My friends!
My frıends!
The Shahada time has come!
The time...
...of clash is also here!
Allahu akbar!
Bala!
Tell your people to stop right there.
My kin!
We can't be defeated!
Arm your swords!
Playing the mute devil does not exist in
our culture!
The time...
of Shahada is here!
Allahu Akbar!
Osman.
Brother.
My Osman has arrived.
Your power is unquestionable my Rab.
Thank you.
Balgay!
Welcome to Balgay's Hell, Osman.
I came here to clean our Tents.
You and your men...
...better stop this persecution.
Do you know what I see when I look at you?
A carcass that is chopped into pieces
to feed the hounds.
That's your reflection on
the mirror, Balgay.
I offered you bannerlordship...
...but you refused.
Then, I told you I'll be your death.
A word leaves my mouth only once.
I always keep my promises, Osman Bey.
You are dead now!
I came here not to obey...
...but to give you the might of Genghis
Khan.
The might of Genghis Khan is not a joke.
What might are you talking about?
Now, you'll either listen to me...
...or lose your luck.
I have a treasure no Mongol commander can
reject.
While the might of Genghis Khan flows in
my noble veins...
...how do you dare to talk like this?
Genghis Khan says...
...listen to your enemy well when...
...he stands in front you with consent
and courage.
So that...
...you can prove you are as valiant your
enemy.
Or else...
...are you telling me that you are not
courages enough, Balgay?
Commander Balgay.
Emissaries from Konya are approaching.
These are the ones Geyhatu sent before.
You have news from Geyhatu, Balgay.
Geyhatu wants you.
He wants me to send your Alps to Konya.
How did you meet Geyhatu?
What are you up to, Osman?
Geyhatu appreciates the treasure I know.
I have been waiting for him.
What is that treasure Geyhatu wants to
posses so much?
What are you up to, Osman?
Hush, Hatun.
Hush!
He knows what is doing.
Soldiers!
Put your swords down.
Tonga!
Cankutay!
Stop the executions!
Take the captives.
It is an order from Geyhatu.
What happened?
Don't care about that.
Osman ruined all of our plans.
He wasted Alişar and Balgay.
He got Nizamettin killed.
And now, Balgay.
Mongols!
They came to our land, along with...
their bad smell and greed.
You can have the same enemy with Mongols.
But you should never be friends with them.
My daughter.
Curse be upon them.
We should no longer expect anything from
Balgay the Uncivilized.
I had kiss his dirty hands.
The more I think of it, the more I get
disgusted.
Balgay is an absolute trouble.
He neither gets anything nor listens to
us.
However, he is not our only hope.
There may be another way to our salvation.
Salvador!
Can we trust Salvador, master?
He might play a double game.
We can't know without trying, Sofia.
We will try.
Both Salvador and the Mongols.
Remember the person you know the best...
...is your partner crime, Princess.
And, I know Mongols the best.
We will present Constantinople to them.
They are powerful enough to take it.
In this way, you will be the Queen.
And one day, you will be very surprised
when...
...your Mongol King dies all of a sudden.
You are coming to my Tent, Osman Bey,
We need to talk somewhere private.
You may come with us, Dündar Bey.
What are you talking about Osman?
What does ''the Might of Genghis Khan"
mean?
I won't let them hurt our people, uncle.
You should trust me.
You must be respectful in front of Balgay.
You, Turk!
I want to learn what he has to say.
I am not here for childish games, Balgay.
Think twice before you talk.
Stop messing around.
I am listening.
Speak!
I don't take orders from Mongols.
Uncle!
What's the matter, son?
Is this dagger I'm holding right now...
..."Law Defender"?
It's the exact dagger...
...that defended Genghis Khan's laws.
He lost his mind.
My Bey came here to bring us salvation.
Praise him!
I was a captive some time ago.
Ertugrul Bey saved me as fast as he could.
My brothers!
We will not let them survive on these
lands.
The situation is different this time
Valiants.
I saw so many Mongols in my life.
However, Balgay is different...
...and stronger than the rest of them.
In order to remain the one and only rulers
of these lands.
To defeat him.
You should also trick him and make plans.
Once we are free, if I can't teach
them some lessons.
If I can't make them learn about how to
respect us.
I will not be able to feel like a soldier
anymore.
Where did you find this?
Commander Balgay.
Osman is lying.
A Turk couldn't posses the mighty
dagger of Genghis Khan.
Balgay!
It seems like you could not raise your
men properly.
They question your authority.
If all of your men are like these two.
You won't be able to conquer
Constantinople.
Take all the bounties to your people and
punish your enemies.
Law Defender.
I have the Laws of Genghis Khan...
...written by Şigi Kutugu
Do you have the forgotten laws of mighty
Genghis Khan?
Do you have any idea what that means?
Where is it?
Hand it to me at once!
Only under some conditions.
Tell me right now!
You will free my Alps.
You will leave our lands.
You will give our golds back.
And you will promise in front of all Beys.
I came here...
...to kill those who try to rise
against me.
If the things you say are not true...
...I will destroy the Kayı Tent with my
army today.
Just for your information.
May our sorrow end.
May we break free.
May the gates of heaven be open.
i seek protection in Allah
from the accursed shaytan.
In the name of Allah,
the Beneficent, the Merciful
Indeed, We have given you,
[O Muhammad], a clear conquest
Surah Al-Fath [48]
That Allah may forgive for you
what preceded of your sin
and what will follow and complete His favor upon you and guide you to a straight path
And [that] Allah may aid
you with a mighty victory.
It is He who sent down tranquillity into the hearts of the believers that they would increase in faith along with their [present] faith.
And to Allah belong the soldiers of the heavens and the earth, and ever is Allah Knowing and Wise.
Surah Al-Fath [48]
My Osman...
...will not surrender to Balgay's order.
We all need to be careful these days.
We might have to fight our enemies any day
now. The war might be on our door.
And this time the consequences can be
much worse, my Bey.
As long as we are together...
...nothing can stop us.
All we need to do is just believe.
We'll put it out, my lovely child.
We'll put it out.
The treasure you have brought blessed me.
I have come one step closer to
my ancestor Genghis' soul in the sky.
You asked for Beys. Now they are here.
Say what you want to say.
We manage our Tents with laws...
... our laws with our meetings.
But a meeting doesn't begin this way.
In the ninety-nine names of Allah
who has the power to create
and who fills our hearts with faith.
Valiant Beys of Kayı.
I have the Genghis' laws, which are also
valued greatly by Balgay.
These laws are very important for
a Mongol commander.
Because Mongols have been following
traces for these treasures.
Now I have them.
I'll bring those laws, and Balgay will
leave the Tent in return.
He'll release our Alps.
I wanted him to promise in front of you.
- Thank you.
My ancestor Genghis!
- speaking in Mongol -
Watch yourself when you're alone.
Watch your word when you're not.
He said.
I'm Balgay. I've made my promise.
If Osman also keeps his promise...
I swear I'll do what he said.
But...
If these are tricks within tricks...
I'll burn your goats and dogs! Know that!
I won't even let your babies live!
Then...
... it's my job to keep my promise.
- Speak.
- Master...
Osman is dangerous!
Even if there are a lot of people
around him, he's like a lone wolf.
It's true that he's alone.
The Mongols have all his Alps.
Just like how he has all my soldiers.
Let me go find out what
he's doing and where he is.
You might be lying.
You might fight against us
with Osman again.
One can escape death
a lot of times, Salvador.
But no one runs forever.
Do you understand?
Yes, Master.
Trust me. I'll serve you in this battle.
I will not die before I give you
Osman and redeem myself.
If you make one mistake...
... I'll skin you alive.
My Osman! My Osman.
What did that infidel Balgay say?
He will keep his promise, Bamsı Bey.
Don't you worry.
He'll leave our Tent.
He'll release our Alps.
Good, my Osman. But where did those
Genghis Khan laws come from?
Who gave them to you, my Osman?
It's a secret, Bamsı Bey.
I can't say anything else.
Son!
How can a friend hide
something from his fellow?
There are things friends can't do,
Bamsı Bey.
My Osman, these lands were
empty when we came.
We paved these roads with
our blood, our lives!
My Osman, this situation disturbs me.
Tell me. What is the truth?
- Don't push me, Bamsı Bey.
- Osman!
Don't push it, Bamsı Bey!
I can't say more.
We don't call this friendship.
Either we were wrong...
... or we couldn't teach you that.
It's obvious why Geyhatu
wants Gengis' Laws from Osman, Balgay.
Whoever has the laws,
has the power, Cerkutay.
no one can stand in their way.
If Osman brings the laws, you'll be
the might and the power in these lands.
Me having them is not the point.
How did Osman find this dagger which
was protecting Genghis Khan's laws?
How could Geyhatu know this?
I didn't ask Osman where he found it.
Why would he think I fell into his trap?
I shall acquire the power first.
I'll figure it out when the time comes.
If Osman brings the laws...
... will you give them to Geyhatu?
He'll take them himself. If he can.
I'll take him to the Mongol Khanate
myself.
Balgay will finally be in a
position he deserves!
What's the status?
Balgay took the bait.
I'll take care of the rest.
Then go, my Osman! The world is yours!
Go! The mountains, the rivers
shall follow your way!
I never thought I'd pray for Osman.
Poor Zöhre.
You're relying on the mad man Osman
for your son's life.
We're not relying on anyone, Hatun!
Do you think I'll let that infidel
Balgay decide my son's fate?
I'll face him if necessary, but I
won't let him touch my son!
Watch your words!
Don't make me go mental!
I'm worried about my son, Dündar Bey!
I hope Osman takes care
of this as soon as possible.
If he does, not only me, the whole Tent
will see him as a Bey.
Instead of screaming at me, think about
what you'll do when that day comes.
I say the last word in the Kayı Tent.
Osman also knows this very well.
Osman tied a knot,
he will untie it himself.
It's not about meetings, being a Bey,
or about Bala.
Not that much.
They tortured you a lot, Sıddık.
They did. But it was worth it, Osman Bey.
Besides, is being Sıddık easy?
Tell me. What's the status?
I convinced Yannis and Sofia. They sent
me to gather information about you.
Then we'll give them what they want.
So that they trust you more.
What do you want me to say?
Tell them I'm about to save
the Tent from Balgay.
They will ask how.
I have something that can excite Balgay.
Genghis Khans' laws.
They will worry about this.
If they worry, they
will fall into the trap.
Now go. Do as I say.
You couldn't do anything to tied men.
Are you trying your luck on women now?
Degenerate!
Mongol dog!
Look at me!
What? Are you scared?
You haven't talked since Osman Bey came.
Don't!
- Konur!
- Dog!
Don't you worry.
It will be your turn soon!
All of yours!
Devil's son! Just wait.
I'll strangle you myself.
If I don't pull your flesh from
your bones, I shall not be called Konur!
Your eyes are not slanted.
You're not short either.
Tell me. What did this Mongol give you
so you became his puppy?
I see.
You're a numbskull.
Numbskull.
What did you call me? Repeat if you're
a man. Tell me!
If I don't pull your flesh from your bones
I shall not be called Konur, numbskull!
Untie him!
Mongol dog!
Get him up!
Don't!
Infidel!
Göktuğ. Göktuğ come here, son.
Mother! Look I have the same one.
Of course, you do, son. All of our
men have it since your grandfather.
- Father!
- Father.
- Konur! Göktuğ!
- My Bey...
- Father!
- My Bey!
Father!
You degenerate!
You dog!
I'll teach you how to laugh.
Don't rely on Osman Bey to save you.
As long as we're here, this world
will be hell for you!
Konur!
Balgay's words. Until he says
something, they will live.
Konur!
Selamın Aleyküm
(Peace be upon you)
Aleyküm Selam.
(Peace be upon you too)
Since you're here safe and sound, you've
rekindled Balgay's desire for power.
Now I will save my brothers, my Selcan
mother, my Tent from Balgay's wrath.
Then, if Allah permits, our first
great battle will begin.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
( in the name of Allah, the merciful and compassionate.)
I took care of it well.
May Allah bless you, my Sheikh.
Your first battle with the Mongols.
First battles are harsh.
They're very hard.
When our Prophet, with his companion,
started his first battle of Badr...
... non-muslims were underestimating
the holy army with their arrogance.
They were bragging about their power.
Because of that, they
underestimated Muslims.
But our Prophet was always alert.
Our Prophet went to the
battlefield of Badr before non-muslims...
... and had the shafts closed one by one.
He made moves to compensate for his
weakness in the hot weather of the desert.
After completing his preparations...
... he started praying.
The Prophet of mercy trusted Allah
with his army.
And my Allah answered his prayers.
My Rab says, in the surah Ali İmran...
While you were weaker in Badr,
Allah helped you and made you victorious.
Live by Allah's words...
... so that you'll be grateful.
I hope my Allah supports us with army of
Angels so that we'll be victorious.
It's up to you, Osman.
What do you mean, my Sheikh?
Don't lose your sincerity and faith.
Do everything with passion.
A job without passion
won't yield good results.
But this passion shouldn't just be love.
Our Prophet was stoned for
his love for Allah in Ta'if.
He didn't bow to the cruel.
The enemy couldn't scare him.
You shouldn't lose your passion...
... while setting your table,
swinging your sword...
... while talking in a meeting, or
listening to someone's troubles.
If you lose it...
... you'll lose your consciousness.
The devil will enslave you.
Make your mind one with passion, my son.
So that these dark clouds over
the world of Islam can go away.
So that the hopelessness comes to an end.
So that laziness comes to an end.
So that the fire of resurrection
can be rekindled.
Hopefully, my Sheikh.
I'll try my best.
I'll fight until the end!
Come on. Balgay will go mad
if we talk for too long.
- Ya Allah!
- Ya Bismillah!
Konur.
What are you thinking, son?
Nothing, mother.
Tell me.
I had a small mind. Kungar took it.
What are you talking about, son?
Please don't be him. Please don't be him.
My Allah, please.
What is it, Princess?
Did you lose your way?
What are you doing in our Tent?
I'm here to say "Get well soon".
Come here.
Did the Mongols hurt you much?
Osman Bey probably worries about you.
They ruined you.
Look at them!
My Allah, forgive me.
We weren't Tentless for a thousand years,
and weren't obsolete for a thousand years.
If we were to be scared of snakes
like you and Balgay...
... we wouldn't be standing
in front of you right now.
You're talking to me, tied
in your own dungeon.
You're miserable.
My Osman made Balgay kick
Alişar like the dog he is.
Alişar is gone. Now is this Princess after
Balgay's mattress?
What is it, Princess?
My words hurt the Princess' arrogance.
You're dying to take the life
Balgay couldn't.
I'll only laugh to that, Sofia.
When your Tent is covered in your blood...
... the last thing you'll see will be
my laughing eyes.
Selcan Hatun.
We will not die without putting
those eyes of yours out!
Without seeing you skinned alive...
... I will not die.
I will come to your funerals.
Look at us.
My dear Allah...
No words from Osman Bey either.
We don't know what he's doing.
How are we going to put up with this?
Kill us. Kills us! Kill us!
Kill us!
Friends!
Brothers!
Allah says in the Quran...
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
( in the name of Allah, the merciful and compassionate.)
Unless you go through which
those before you went through...
... you cannot enter heaven.
Having faith with words is easy.
But having patience during
trials is hard, brothers.
Brothers!
Patience, brothers!
Patience.
Patience, my Allah.
How can this woman come to our Tent?
I'll go take a look.
Let me go! What is that
snake Sofia doing in my Tent?
You won't leave your Tent before
Osman Bey comes!
If she comes to the Tent after killing
countless valiants of ours...
... they are working with Balgay.
They won't stop before killing us all.
I should have killed that snake
the first time she came to the Tent.
You never do things in time, Dündar Bey.
You didn't listen to me when I told you
to look after Osman.
"Stop Edebali" I said. You didn't listen.
Now they have joined forces and they are
taking our Tent and our lives!
Zöhre. Enough.
They are going to take away our son.
They will break us.
It's all because of Osman.
If they kill my son...
I will haunt you in the afterworld!
Hatun, I said enough.
Enough!
You couldn't protect this tent.
You couldn't take care of Osman.
- Are you taking it all out of me now?
- Enough!
Come on, hit me!
You can fear only me.
Enough already.
Enough, enough enough!
Enough.
You will crawl into Balgay's presence,
Hatun.
What did you bring me?
Efendi Yannis aroused the spies in
Byzantine.
We are ready for the big war.
As I said to Yannis...
Every information coming from castles...
from landlords, from Emperor's
armies...
should be brought to me first.
Don't doubt that.
The landlord of Yakhisar will come to see
you. He will not die before he sees you.
The rest is your Nökers'(soldier) job.
Get up.
What else will you give me?
This doesn't work, me giving all the time,
Balgay.
I want you to keep your promises.
How dare you talk to me like that,
Princess?
Why didn't you kill Osman and his Alps
when they came to you?
How do you know that Osman is
in the tribe?
I said I have eyes everywhere.
Even in Turks' tent.
Didn't you believe us?
I freed Osman.
Genghis Khan's laws.
Why are they so important?
So, you also know about this.
And you believed Osman.
Right?
He will get what he wants when he
brings the laws.
I swore on Genghis Khan's laws.
Let's say he brought them.
Then what?
Once I get what I want to get...
Then you can face with Osman.
Osman Bey is coming, Commander
Balgay.
Let's see.
Genghis Khan's laws, ha?
Are you dreaming of being an Empress of
Constantinopolis with your new owner, Sofia?
My eyes are sharper than yours.
My ears are better than yours.
My weapon is sharper than yours.
Osman, you are trying to
bite off more than you can chew.
If you are desiring death so much, don't
tire us.
I will face you someday, Sofia.
And that day is soon.
Did you bring Genghis Khan's laws?
Hmh?
I want to see, but I have lots of things
to do in the castle.
Say hi to Yannis.
I will see you again.
Say hi to Edebalı.
"Sofia will kill you soon."
Did you bring it?
Yes.
Bring it to me.
Don't forget the word you gave in front
of Beys.
Keep your promise.
Get out of my father's place.
Enough.
Give me the law.
Keep your promise.
Release my alps.
Get your Nökers(soldiers) out of
my tent.
Power...
is with me.
If you don't keep your promise, Geyhatu'll
figure out that you have Genghis Khan's laws.
An alp of mine is waiting to notify
Geyhatu.
Do you know why I offered you to
be banner lord?
In time, Genghis Khan's biggest enemies...
had been his best friends...
his best Commanders.
In a fight, a valiant shot an arrow
to Genghis Khan.
And succeeded to injure him.
After the war was over, his Commander
Tayhatlu went to the captivities.
He asked who shot that arrow.
A soldier came to the front with
courage and said " I shot it."
Genghis Khan was impressed by his courage
and made him the Commander of his army...
and also gave him Cebe name, which means
arrow.
Cebe has been one of the greatest
Commanders of Mongol Army.
Firstly, I am Allah's creature, then
Ertuğrul Ghazi's son.
We obey Allah, and then our tradition.
Now, get out of the tent with
your soldiers.
Can I come in, Bamsı Bey?
Come, Nuğrul.
- Osman Bey has come.
- So, it is time.
We can't trust that Balgay dog.
Lions, you heard me. I will slaughter them
if they don't keep their promise.
- Is the carriage ready?
- Everything is ready, my Bey.
- You trained us for this day, for sure.
- Masha Allah(praise be) my valiant.
Mongol infidels will see what it takes
to conquer Muslim lands.
You have gazelle eyes, but you have
a wolf's heart. Masha Allah my daughter.
Osman brought Genghis Khan's laws.
No one can stop Balgay now.
Samsa Bey.
How did Osman find that?
I don't know how he got it but...
Osman Bey will gather all the Mongols
while trying to save us.
Samsa Bey...
Osman Bey must know something.
Sure. There are so many things that
he knows but we don't, brother.
Today, the souls gave you hope, and
they gave me power.
Cerkutay, set the captives free.
They should know that Balgay
has spared their lives.
Dündar Bey.
Notify the near Beys immediately.
Say that "Go to Balgay's presence."
"Balgay wants to see if there's someone who
is thirsty for his blood.
who looks for trouble...
who rides for a fall."
Tell them to come to me to obey me.
How did you get Cengiz Han's laws, eh?
Why don't I know about that, Osman?
Uncle...
I saved valiants' lives and protected the
tribe.
Now, you need to think about how
you will manage my father's place.
From now on, I don't want any rebellion.
Watch your steps.
My Batur was going to die because of you.
You were almost going to poison my son
like you did to your Alps.
This is the poison of freedom, Uncle.
When it mixes with the blood, it doesn't
go away, if you are a real man.
They will destroy the Tent because of
your stubbornness!
Enough already.
They destroy the Tent or you obey
Balgay like a dog. Doesn't matter.
Get out of that place so that someone
qualified can run this tribe!
Who will take my place when I quit?
- Who!?
- I will!
Ertuğrul Ghazi's son Osman!
There's a meeting tonight.
You'll answer, Osman.
You'll answer.
We can't trust them. Observe both Kayı
Tent and Samsa's Tent.
As you command, Balgay.
Get out of here!
Osman found a way to save his tribe.
How did he manage that?
- How did he get Genghis Khan laws?
- Sir...
Perhaps this is Edebalı and Ahis' job.
Damn Edebalı and Ahis.
Not Edebalı. Even he can't do this.
There must be something else.
But what is that?
- Salvador, didn't Osman say anything?
- No sir.
Whatever this secret is, Osman hides
it to death.
Then he will not be able to hide it
so long.
As soon as Balgay gives up on him...
I will hunt Osman down.
We have a hound who shows us the way.
He knows our prey very well.
Moreover, everything he said until now
has been proved true.
I told you I wouldn't die before
redeeming myself, sir Yannis.
I know where he hides Edebalı.
We will hunt them all at once.
Osman.
Thank Allah you are okay.
Thank Allah.
Salvation is soon, Bala Hatun.
We will repel Mongols, inshallah.
How did you manage that, Osman Bey?
Genghis Khan's laws have been absent
for years.
How did you find it?
There is a saying " The helper doesn't
show up when you are not in need."
Let's say the helper has arrived.
Who is that helper, Osman Bey?
It's secret, Bala Hatun.
Won't you tell me, Osman Bey?
Won't you tell the woman who you love,
who you would set the whole world on fire?
Now, know that...
if you want to share a life with me...
you are not going to know my secrets.
You will stop when I say so.
You will keep silent when silence
is needed.
I am an Ahi daughter, Osman Bey.
If I am going to be a friend to my husband,
I want to know his secrets.
I want to stand like a mountain
on his side.
I want to fight together.
I am not like other Hatuns.
If you allow...
It's all yours.
Salamu alaykum.
- Salamu alaykum.
- Alaykum salam.
You did it.
You saved us, my Bey.
What is it, Sergeant Samsa?
You are staying away.
How did this happen, Osman Bey?
How did that infidel release us?
There's always a key for every lock,
Samsa Bey.
The important thing is who owns the key.
You are wrong, Samsa Bey.
The important thing is whether the
key works or not.
That key worked, so we are free now.
What is friendship, Osman Bey?
What is brotherhood?
Why don't you tell us?
No one gave us our freedom, Samsa Bey.
We took it.
I can't tell this to anyone.
I thought we were like a chain of mountains
when we stood back to back.
But I was wrong.
I, the great Samsa Bey, ignored my
personality and served you like an Alp.
Samsa Bey, we are facing the cruels.
We are going through difficult times.
- If we don't tolerate each other...
- Apparently, we are not close now.
Apparently, for you,
the wind blows in reverse.
When I feel that I am not trusted...
I no longer continue that way.
- Samsa Bey.
- So, this is it.
Now that a secret is between us, I can
walk the freedom way alone.
I give my blessings to you.
Happiness is Genghis Khan's
Law is Balgay's.
Genghis Khan's soul is in me.
His law is with me!
From now on...
From now on, with Genghis Khan's soul...
with his power...
To north, to south, to east, to west...
to lands, to seas, to mountains, and
to sky...
I am the ruler!
The souls are with me.
My anger is in me.
My blood is boiling
Here, in front of you,
my valiant soldiers...
my loyal Nökers...
in front of my deceased
ancestors' souls...
and in front of the soul of almighty
Genghis Khan.
I will seal Genghis Khan's law
in my tongue!
This is Balgay's swear in front of...
my Nökers whose friends are our
ancestors' souls.
We set off to rule the whole world.
We went beyond Gobi Desert,
Tengri Mountains, and the Caspian Sea.
Our destination is Constantinople.
Our way is bloody!
Blood!
Neither Byzantine's dogs nor peevish
Turks...
can stop us.
Rebels like Osman...
will be material for our shaman drums.
We will rise upon their bodies by banging
their skins with their bones!
We will swim in their blood!
Crush me if I stop.
Trample me under your horses
if I get exhausted.
You shall be my enemy if you stop!
If you stop, you shall suffer forever...
in the souls hands!
I am sealing Genghis Khan's law
in my tongue.
Happiness is Genghis Khan's
Law is Balgay's.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
[in the name of Allah, the merciful and compassionate.]
With Allah's ninety nine names...
who can make things happen with
a single voice.
My Beys, we are going through difficult
days.
Mongols said they went away, but they
may come back anytime.
We are here to review our situation.
I've been in Kayı tent for years.
I've never heard of anyone
doing something without Bey's knowledge.
Osman, without the council's and your
knowledge, did things about Mongols...
Dündar Bey.
We have heard that you declined Balgay's
offer of being a banner lord.
How can you do that?
If Osman had accepted this great offer
in the view of politics...
those things wouldn't happen now.
Wouldn't happen for now.
What about the future?
Our descendants will think that...
we've been enslaved by Mongols.
They'll think we've run away and
we've not struggled for freedom.
I ask you.
In this world, which we couldn't rule...
will we bow down to Mongols?
Will we receive orders?
Will we be slaves?
You don't talk right, my nephew.
You're after some dreams.
Will you defeat Mongols, who
rule the world?
I will.
You will.
Dündar Bey will.
Gündüz Bey will.
Our blacksmith will.
Şahin Bey will.
We can defeat cruels...
like how my father Kürşat have burnt
the great wall of China...
like how my father Alparslan have brought
Romanos Diogenes to his knees...
like how my father Selahattin have taken
Jerusalem.
We should believe in ourselves.
We don't want to hear nonsense, Osman.
We don't want chaos anymore.
This is a tent, Şahin Bey.
There's a price for living in this land.
If someone doesn't pay for it...
is destined to disappear.
We're here because we've
paid for it, Gündüz Bey.
We want silence now.
- We want to rest.
- The ones who want to rest...
shouldn't be in this tent.
The ones who shouldn't
be in this tent are...
the ones who get into trouble.
What do you mean, blacksmith?
Mongols are closer now.
If we rebel, they'll kill us.
We supported Osman because...
he was the son of Ertuğrul Ghazi.
But it's not bearable anymore.
Osman...
Osman should leave the tent.
I thought you'd be happy.
But you're angry.
Osman Bey wants a slave, not a wife.
What are you saying, Bala?
He wants a wife like the women who
milk cows in his tent.
I don't underrate them.
I am sorry because
he doesn't know me well.
He doesn't what kind of Hatun I am.
Bala.
If he doesn't, you know who you love.
And the real skill is...
how to tame the mad horses.
Ah, Osman.
Ah.
- It's Osman's moves that save us.
- You're wrong, Gündüz Bey.
It's Osman's moves that
have brought the Mongols here.
You don't see the things in front of you.
Sofia came here.
The bad people are together and they
are alliances.
Your only wish is to stay alive.
What about your honor?
When you followed my father, didn't you
know that these would happen to you?
Tell me.
Uncle.
What about you?
I came to these lands
having fought in many wars.
We decided everything together...
with your father, my brother
Ertuğrul Ghazi.
No one in this tent can be a
callow as much as you.
I told you many times, but...
you didn't listen.
The tent was routed. Söğüt is
about to fall.
No one can resist a second strike.
What about you, Bamsı Bey?
You don't say anything.
What do you say?
Blacksmith...
and Şahin Bey...
are right.
The tent needs to be...
in peace, as soon as possible.
Dündar Bey...
the decision is yours.
What about you, Abdurrahman Ghazi?
You dedicated your life to Kayı's fight.
You were the adjutant of Ertuğrul Ghazi.
What do you say?
Oghuzs' condition are apparent.
The safety of the tent...
is the most important.
Bamsı Bey is right.
I agree.
For the safety of my tent...
I approve the
exile of Osman.
Your heart is frustrated.
Do you object my words?
If you talk again, I'll
send you to exile too.
I'd rather die with Osman...
than being captured here.
So that my absence will
bring peace to the tent...
then I'll go.
But don't forget.
Freedom is gained with weapons...
not with peace and...
facility.
"Assalamu alaikum wa rahmatullah"
(peace and the mercy of Allah be on you)
I have the same.
My Allah...
you've been testing Konur for years.
I'm tired of longings.
You see the best of me...
and you know me well.
If...
the person who serves the Mongols...
is my brother Göktuğ...
you help him search for the right way.
If he doesn't have faith...
let me kill him with my own hands.
Exile.
- What are you saying, my Boran?
- Were going into exile tomorrow.
Bamsı Bey? How did he let this?
He and Abdurrahman Ghazi
wanted us to go, brother.
Osman Bey said
we'd arrive Samsa Bey's tent.
Sergeant Samsa? What if he
doesn't want us?
I don't know, brother.
My Boran. It's too bad.
Can I come in, Bamsı Bey?
Come in, Selcan Hatun.
Bamsı Bey...
That's unexpected.
You're the half father
of Osman, you're his mentor...
and you're his enemy now.
I'm telling you, Bamsı Bey.
Why do you turn away from him?
Why do you leave him?
Selcan Hatun, stop.
Mongol fire burnt our tent.
You saw it too.
Mongols are like storms.
- Bamsı Bey.
- Selcan Hatun.
Beys are angry with him. He does
everything without asking.
Osman should leave.
So that he can pull himself together and
he can't be a novice.
Selcan Hatun, you know.
If Osman remains the
same, the tent will be miserable.
Selcan Hatun, don't worry.
I'll protect my Osman.
Forgive me, Bamsı Bey.
I have the heart of a mother.
That's why I'm anxious.
- Give me your blessings.
- Selcan Hatun.
I know. Thanks.
-Tashahhud Surah-
"Assalamu alaikum wa rahmatullah" (peace and the mercy of Allah be on you)
My Allah...
If I'm struggling for myself...
pull me together.
If I'm struggling for reputation...
destroy me.
My only desire...
is to gain your consent.
If my desire...
becomes
reputation...
kill me.
I'm leaving, father.
I'm leaving.
But I'm proud.
I did everything for this tent.
I didn't bow down to the landlord.
I didn't bow down to the Mongols.
I learnt how to hold my head high
from you.
I learnt courage fom Bamsı Bey.
I learnt loyalty from Abdurrahman Ghazi.
Now I'm leaving.
But I'll come back.
Son.
You're the right owner of this tent.
- Dündar Bey sent you.
- No one can send me from this tent.
I won't go into exile.
If I stay, I'll have to depend on
Dündar Bey.
You know, I can't.
Come back soon. You know...
Dündar Bey isn't the one who'll
glorify the Kayıs.
What would we do without you?
Don't worry.
I won't leave this tent...
which my grandfather Süleyman Şah
and my father Ertuğrul Ghazi ruled.
If I don't go now, it'll be hard for
me to obey Dündar Bey.
It will.
If I go...
when the tiime comes, I''ll go back
with freedom and power...
and then people can support
Dündar Bey if they want...
or they can start fighting with me.
- Give me your blessings.
- I will.
Osman left with his Alps.
Finally, he got what he deserved.
Thanks to Allah. We got
rid of his troubles.
You don't know what you're doing.
You have focused on your darkness and
you don't see the light of Osman.
Shame on you.
Batur!
Where are you going?
I can't stay in this tent.
What are you saying, son?
Can your hear what you've just said?
My place is somewhere else now.
Osman's exile opened my eyes.
Give me your blessings, mother.
- Son... Brother.
- Let him go!
He can go to hell.
Will you let him go, Dündar Bey?
If we'll suppurate, we'll start it
with our children.
From now on...
I don't have a child named Batur.
I don't.
- Your son is gone! Your son!
- I don't have a son named Batur.
Saltuk!
Yes, my Bey.
Go to Bahadır. I forgave him.
He should return. He should be
with me on these hard days.
Your command, my Bey.
After all these problems, will
we deal with Batur?
Your son and you debased me.
I wish I couldn't send Bahadır
and his mother.
Our tent won't support Dündar Bey anymore.
It's our duty to protect Kayıs reputation
and make life unbearable for Mongols.
It's our duty, my Bey.
What about Osman Bey? He was your friend.
Osman Bey and I splitted.
We're alone from now on.
Can I come in, Samsa Bey?
I don't even have a word for those
who hide secrets from his friend.
That secret made us free, Samsa Bey.
Mongols made us their slaves.
And you came with an idea that you
don't even say where you've got it from.
Now that you want something else?
My secret is a secret, Sergeant Samsa.
There's nothing else.
Your secret is a secret.
Good.
Are there any other
secrets you hide? Tell me.
Is this how a friendship is like?
How can I trust you now?
How can I send my Alps to death?
If there's a secret, there
won't be a belief, Osman Bey.
You're going too far, Sergeant Samsa.
You're a hero, Osman Bey.
You're great, Osman Bey.
You're brave, Osman Bey.
But you're novice.
- Pull yourself together, Sergeant Samsa!
- You're novice.
We've been friends but...
you're being cruel!
You don't have a place in this
tent, novice Osman!
That's not a friendship, Osman!
- Boran.
- Konur, stop.
- Boran, should we go inside?
- Stop, brother.
We'll be harmed.
Let's wait.
Is that all, Sergeant Samsa?
You should've not done that to me.
It's hard to establish a state with
people who rebel and run away.
Everyone will rebel if I give a chance to you.
You shouldn't rebel me.
I ran out of patience.
Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com